Nick Bolles

https://www.NickBolles.com | https://Portfolio.NickBolles.com www.LinkedIn.com/in/NickBolles | www.Github.com/NickBolles

10210 Rustling Birch Rd. Apt 221 Verona, WI 53593 (715) 781-5549 me@NickBolles.com

About Me

Hey! I'm Nick! I love development, business philosophy, and discovering new technologies. I have experience with a wide array of technologies, with a passion for web development and emerging technologies. I take an iterative approach to development by emphasizing clean code, unit testing, CI/CD, open source and standards-based technology. I also have a business focused mindset; I enjoy brainstorming ways to solve business challenges with technology solutions to achieve efficient, effective, and low cost results.

I spend much of my free time doing hobby development, focusing on the javascript ecosystem and learning new technology. I have developed a few large apps, mostly for learning purposes and they are available on my Gitlab server/Portfolio page. Check my website for more info and links to my LinkedIn, Github and the Gitlab server that I run. For all code examples check my Portfolio/ Gitlab server.

Some of my Skills

- Strong understanding of business and how technology can influence day-to-day business operations
- Strong knowledge of the software development process and how aspects affect business outcomes
- Excellent development skills including: Typescript/ESNext, Angular (1.x and 2+), React, Vue, SASS/CSS, NodeJS, Feathersjs, MongoDB, GraphQL, .Net, REST, Design patterns, Database design, and more
- Extensive experience with software development tools and methods such as Git, SVN, Docker, Jasmine, Mocha, Github/Gitlab, Gitlab CI/CD, Jira, NPM, Webpack, Gulp, Cordova, Balsamiq, Agile, Scrum etc.

Experience

Epic, Verona WI - *Software Developer*

June 2017 - Present

- Full stack developer (MUMPS, .Net, Typescript) responsible for project design, development, and testing
- Application point person for several areas, such as performance testing and training tools
- Learn to formulate viable solutions to complex challenges that large software companies struggle with
- Assisted in establishing new area of ownership for complex and company-wide integrated functionality
- Designed and developed batch edit tool to save thousands of hours a year across the healthcare industry
 - o Effectively organize designs and project timeline to accommodate for challenges encountered
 - Established robust guardrails & error management processes to further reduce management time
 - Work with Epic's framework built on .Net (C#) and the client code (Typescript and SASS) to efficiently show progress and a massive amount of results to the user with great UX

Epic, Verona WI - Software Developer Intern

May 2016 - August 2016

- Designed and developed a mobile IOS app in Swift
- Effectively communicated with end users and mentors to incorporate feedback into design
- Implemented a working prototype and presented to peers and division leaders

Geodigital, Mendota Heights, MN - Software Developer Intern

May 2014 - January 2016

- Completed a self driven project to develop a dynamic documentation system for web services
- Only summer intern to secure a position beyond the scheduled internship end date of August 2014
- Develop numerous javascript features to enhance. Net web app
- Worked with Delphi, SQL, JQuery, .Net

Education

University of Wisconsin - Whitewater - *Double Major*

September 2013 - May 2017

- Bachelor of Business Administration in Information Technology Emphasis on Business Analysis
- Bachelor of Science in Computer Science